1942年春
希特勒的U型潜艇横行北大西洋
击沉盟军舰船逾千艘
威胁美国至英国的补给线
因为无法破解U型潜艇密码
盟军在海战上连连失利
猎杀U- 571
敌船时速8节 方向60度
Enemy speed eight. Angle on the bow, sixty.
目标校准
Mark is set.
深度校准
Depth is set.
距离500米
Range five hundred.
设定鱼雷 速度35节
Set torpedo speed. Thirty- five knots.
1号至4号鱼雷管准备扇型发射
Spread shots from tubes one and four!
1号至4号管准备就绪
Tubes one and four ready.
准备...
Spread shots...
发射
Fire!
鱼雷射出
Torpedoes running.
打得好 舰长
Great shot, Captain.
各位 我们炸沉了敌船
We broke their back, Gentlemen.
敌舰向我逼近 航向180度
Fast screws! Bearing 180!
是驱逐舰
A destroyer!
潜至90米 全速前进
Down to ninety meters. Both motors full ahead!
全体船员到船头去
All hands forward!
锁紧鱼雷管出口盖
Seal torpedo hatches!
右方向舵20度
Starboard rudder twenty.
方向舵20度
Rudder at twenty.
检查所有通海阀
Check all hull openings.
转换航向
Come about.
转至200度
Passing 200 degrees.
45米深 急速下潜
Forty- five meters. Fast dive, Captain.
前后平衡翼同时使用
Both hydroplanes, please.
按220度方向航行
Steady at 220 degrees.
敌舰转右
Contact drawing right.
关闭左引擎
Port engine stop.
左引擎关闭
Port engine has stopped.
左引擎半速倒退
Port engine half back.
深水炸弹
Depth charges!
留意 英国佬的炸弹来了
Hold on! The Tommies are crapping all over us!
小心 那是燃料管
Careful, that's fuel leaking!
塞住裂口
Stop that leak!
舰长 已经潜至120米
She's dropped to 120 meters, Captain.
水柜全部排水 上升
Blow all tanks! Surface! Surface!
没有敌踪 上瞭望台放哨
Everything clear. Lookouts to the bridge!
机房答话
Diesel Room! Answer me!
汉斯 报告损毁情况
I need a damage report, Hans!
舰长 机房没有人活命
They're all dead, Captain. All our mechanics.
所有机械师统统殉职
The Chief Mechanic, the fat kid, the whole engine crew. All dead.
左排气舱盖破烂 左引擎被淹
Port exhaust hatch broke. Port diesel is flooded.
轴箱被淹 右引擎
Crankcase is full of seawater. Starboard diesel...
两天前卡死
seized tow days ago.
- 蓄电池呢 - 损坏了
- What about my batteries? - Damaged. 300 Amps bow, 200 stern.
没用了
It's useless!
只能够勉强潜航或者浮航
We have only enough power to dive and maybe maneuver around a bit.
谢谢 汉斯 吩咐大家节省能源
Thank you, Hans. Pass the word to conserve electricity.
- 通讯员 - 舰长
- Radioman! - Captain?
致柏林
To Berlin:
位置 : 85- 32
Location 85- 32.
两台柴油发动机都失灵 只剩电力发动机
Both diesel engines out of service. Electric motors only.
请求救援
Send help.
海军潜艇司令部
他来了 嗨 安迪 你在哪里? 这可是全员宴会
There he is. Hey, Andy! Where you been? It's an all- hands function.
我来介绍 这位是乔安妮 乔安妮 这是安迪 泰勒
Come here. I want you to meet Joanie. Joanie, this is Andy Tyler.
我的好兄弟 军事学院的同学
My best friend. We went to Annapolis together.
- 很高兴见到你 乔安妮 - 送你根拉森雪茄
- Nice to meet you Joanie. - Hey, I got you one of Larson's stogies.
- 致我们海军的下一任副舰长 - 谢谢
- To our navy's next sub skipper. - Thank you.
上尉 等一会跟兄弟们喝几杯
Lieutenant! Gonna hoist up a few beers with the enlisted boys later?
- 我会的 格力斯 - 好
- You got it, Griggs. - All right.
泰勒长官
Mr. Tyler! Mr. Tyler!
介绍我妈妈给你认识好吗?
My mom is here visiting. Can I bring her over to meet you?
- 好啊 扳机 - 他就是我提起的那位长官
Sure thing, Trigger. That's the lieutenant I was talking about.
泰勒长官
Lieutenant Tyler!
你好 珮丹思 路易丝 戴格伦夫人 舰长
Hello there, Prudence, Louise. Mrs. Dahlgren, Captain.
女伴呢 安迪? 你很少单刀赴会
Where's your date, Andy? It's not like you to arrive stag like this.
接到邀请太晚 没来得及找
I'm afraid I couldn't get one on such short notice, ma'am.
舰长 可以跟你谈谈吗?
Captain, could I have a word with you?
- 可以啊 亲爱的 原谅我们? - 好
- Certainly. Darling, will you excuse us? - Okay.
我很快回来
Be right back.
我没得到我的船
I didn't get my boat.
我知道
I know.
恕我直言 长官 只有一个原因才会发生
With all due respect, sir, there's only one way that could've happened,
那就是你保留了你的推荐
and that's if you with held your recommendation.
是的 我只是觉得你还没准备好
That's right. I just don't think you're ready.
我没准备好是什么意思?
What do you mean, I'm not ready?
我在S33号上兢兢业业 尽职尽责
Sir, I have worked my tail off on the S-33. I'm qualified in every area and then some.
- 没有其他执行官比我分数高 - 安迪
- No executive officer has higher marks than I do. - Andy!
你还不具备单独指挥作战的能力
You're just not ready to take on a command of your own.
我已经下了决定 不用多说
Now I've made my decision. It's done.
泰勒长官 你怎么样
Mr. Tyler. How you doing, sir?
在好好休息
Having a good time? Hell, yeah, Chief.
- 你呢? - 我盼望着启航
- How about you? - I'm looking forward to getting underway.
我是个老水手 需要盐分 长官
I'm a sea dog. Need some salt, sir.
他彻底摧毁了我 士官长
He torpedoed me, Chief.
我在S33号服役了9个月
Nine months aboard the S-33,
凡事尽心尽力
doing the best job I know how.
全心全意
Doing everything once and then doing it again,
从未有过行差踏错
just to make sure I didn't miss anything the first time.
你会得到机会的 海军还有其他的指挥岗位
You'll get your chance, sir. There's other commands in the navy.
你早就知道?
You knew?
不告诉我?
Didn't warn me?
我没有资格 长官
Ain't my place, sir.
俱乐部关闭 请离开
Club's secured! Time to go!
走吧 出去 所有人出去
Let's go. Get out. Everyone out.
快点 走吧
Come on, let's go.
中士 什么事?
What's the meaning of this, Sergeant?
- 你是高级人员? - 是的 我是S33 执行官
- You the senior man? - That's right. I'm the X.O. Of the S-33.
他们获准放假48小时
These men have a 48- hour liberty pass.
不 长官 没有假了
No, sir, not no more.
那些船坞把我的船搞什么鬼?
What the hell are those yardbirds doing to my boat?
看上去像该死的纳粹潜艇
Looks like a goddamn Nazi submarine.
嘿 安迪 今日一定是吉日
Hey, Andy. This is a fine navy day.
他们不给我五分钟的时间来完成我的婚礼 五分钟
They wouldn't give me five minutes to consummate my marriage. Five minutes!
- 什么事? - 天晓得 戴帽吧
- What's going on here? - Hell if I know. Put your cover on.
好的
Yes, sir.
- 泰勒长官 召集船员列队 - 是 舰长
- Mr. Tyler, call the crew to quarters. - Aye, Captain.
大家集合 列队
Quarters! Everybody fall in! Let's get in formation now!
大家列队 立正
Let's go! Now! Formation!
戴格伦舰长 全体船员报到 长官
Captain Dahlgren, all crew members present and accounted for, sir!
好 稍息
Very well. At ease.
对不起 中止了你们的休假 我们行程有变
I'm sorry your liberty's been cut short, but our schedule's changed.
立即打点一切 两小时后出航
We have two hours to get stowed for sea and set the maneuvering watch.
拉森长官 让鱼雷手装上四枚最好的鱼雷
Mr. Larson, have your torpedo men load the tubes with their four best fish.
埃米特长官 启动引擎 充电
Mr. Emmett, warm up the diesels and line up a battery charge.
泰勒长官 装齐补给 军械
Mr. Tyler, we have dry stores, ordnance and perishables to get belowdecks.
各位 轮到我们了 就这些了
Gentlemen, it's our turn. That's all.
立正
Attention!
是 舰长
Aye, Captain.
船员解散 大家装载物资
Crew dismissed! You heard the man! Stores load!
你们你有六秒钟的时间穿上内裤和工装裤 转身
You got six seconds to get on your boondockers and dungarees and turn to!
泰勒长官 这次是真的还是演习?
Mr. Tyler, is this for real, or is it a drill?
“轮到我们”... 什么意思?
"It's our turn"... what does that mean?
还以为可以休假两日 发生了什么?
I thought we had a two- day liberty pass. What's going on?
我不知道 我会去打探一下 大家开工去吧
I don't know, but I'm gonna find out. Get your jobs done now.
戴格伦舰长 能告诉我发生了什么吗 长官?
Captain Dahlgren, could you fill me in on what's going on, sir?
我们不去加勒比海巡逻
We're obviously not going to the Caribbean Station.
不去了 我们有特别任务
No, we're not. We're going on a special op.
我们启航后 你会和埃米特 拉森一起得到简报
You'll be briefed with Mr. Emmett and Mr. Larson once we get underway.
- 是 长官 - 安迪 听着
- Aye, sir. - Andy, listen.
在这次任务中我需要最好的你
I'm gonna need the very best from you on this run,
不管你和我有什么分歧
regardless of any differences you may have with me.
在这点上我们清楚了吗?
Are we clear on that?
- 明白 舰长 - 好
- Yes, sir. - Good.
把无线电员韦兹悄悄带去军需部
Now go find Radioman Wentz and quietly escort him to the materiel office.
- 泰勒长官 - 你好 孩子?
- Mr. Tyler. - How are you, son?
我很好 杜克上将 什么风吹你来?
I'm fine, Admiral Duke. What brings you up here?
是他 这是赫希上尉
He does. That's Lieutenant Hirsch.
他这次会坐你的船
He's gonna be riding your boat.
赫希先生会随潜艇出发 全权指挥
You're not working for Sublant on this run. Mr. Hirsch has operational control.
这次行动 你们要尽量提供协助
He's the boss. Anything he wants, he gets.
好的
Fine.
是他吗?
Is this him?
我知道你家来自科布伦茨
I understand your family comes from Koblentz.
莱茵河区的农民
Good Rhine farming folk.
你听得懂我说的吗 温兹先生?
You understand me, Mr. Wentz?
听得懂 长官
Yes, sir.
你能说流利的德语吗? 会不会读写?
Can you speak passable German? Can you read and write it?
或者你只是有德国名字的乡下仔?
Or are you just a farm boy with a German name?
我只是个乡下仔
I an just farm boy.
但我的读写说能力都还不错
One who can read, write and speak quiet well.
战前 我在布朗大学修读德文
I studied German at Brown University before joining the war.
谢谢你 温兹
Thank you, Wentz.
他可以
He'll do.
谢谢 温兹 你可以走了
Thank you, Wentz. That's all for now.
- 上尉 准备启航 - 是 长官 上将
- Lieutenant, prepare the boat to get underway. - Aye, sir. Admiral.
泰勒长官 有个请求
Mr. Tyler, please,
别告诉别人我是半个德国人
don't tell the other guys I'm half German.
他们会恨我的
They'll hate me.
知道了 温兹
Yeah, sure thing, Wentz.
泰勒长官 你好
You all right, Mr. Tyler?
好极了 爱迪
Tiptop, Eddie. Tiptop.
谢谢你批准我休假
Wanna thank you for that liberty pass.
我的女朋友也感谢你
My girl thanks you too.
你是个好人 泰勒长官
You're a good man, Mr. Tyler.
你心肠好
Heart's in the right place.
静候时机吧 皇天不负有心人
Just need to give it some time.
我知道发生了什么事
Yeah, I heard about what happened to you.
我这样低职位 通常...不被注意
That's one of the advantages of bein' seen and... not bein' seen.
你肯定很惊讶我知道这些消息
You'd be surprised some of the shit we mess- doers hear.
小子 轻点放我的鸡蛋
Boy, don't go droppin' my eggs.
该死 失陪了 泰勒长官
Damn. Excuse me, Mr. Tyler.
看看 要你做的只是用双手捧着 用双手
Look, all you gotta do is pick 'em up with both hands, boy, both hands!
泰勒
Tyler!
为什么不早说? 我从士官长那里听来的
When the hell were you gonna tell me? I hear this from the chief.
你想要我说什么?  给他打压
What do you want me to say? He shit- canned me.
可以调去另一艘潜艇
Now you're gonna transfer to another boat.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你们能告诉我在哪里能找到这件事的执行人吗?
Can either one of you two tell me where I can find the exec of this thing?
我是 把你的卡车挪开 一会儿要卸货
Yeah, that's me, mac. Move your truck. We'll unload shortly.
我要立即卸货 这是货物清单
You'll unload it now. Here's the manifest.
- 那些箱子放下面 - 你是谁?
- Get those crates belowdecks. - Who the hell are you?
陆战队少校库南 海军情报部军官
Marine Major Coonan, Office of Naval Intelligence.
我跟你们一起出海
I'm goin' to sea with you boys.
我的行李 你有问题可以问赫希
That's my luggage. You got a problem, talk to Mr. Hirsch.
可以出航
Clear.
解船首缆
Cast off all lines forward!
Cast off forward! Take in all lines aft.
解船尾缆
Cast off aft!
直航 三分一全速
Rudder amidships, all ahead one- third.
三分一全速
All ahead one- third!
瞭望台舱盖关闭
Bridge hatch shut.
机房关闭柴油机 切换电动
Engine room, secure the diesels. Shift propulsion to the battery.
- 主通气阀关闭 - 是
- Main induction indicates shut. - Aye.
- 可以潜水 舰长 - 好
- Green board, Skipper. - Very well.
超越一百英寸等深线 航线正确
Passing the 100- fathom curve. On course, on time, sir.
机房改用电力推动
Engine room reports secured diesels, propulsion switched to battery.
- 三分之二全速 - 三分之二全速
- Very well. All ahead two- thirds. - All ahead two- thirds, aye.
埃米特 开始下潜
Mr. Emmett, take her down.
以10度潜至150英尺
Make her depth 1- 5- 0 feet, ten degree down bubble.
150英尺 10度下潜  是 舰长
One- five- zero feet, ten degree down bubble. Aye, sir.
值更官 开启警号 传令下潜
Chief of the watch, sound the dive alarm. Pass the word to 1 MC.
开启主水柜注水管
Open the main ballast tank vents.
宣布下潜 少尉
Aye, sir, passing the word.
下潜 下潜
Dive, dive, dive.
长官 主水柜注水管开启
Sir, main ballast tank vents indicate open.
前后平衡翼下潜角度15度
Aye. Both planes dive, 15 degrees. Both planes dive, 15 degrees.
四周没有障碍
All clear!
水位升至甲板
Decks awash. Decks awash. Aye, sir.
初次乘搭潜艇?
First time on a submarine?
对
That's right.
60英尺
Six- zero feet.
放下潜望镜
Lower the scope.
曲轴箱和海水泵出现轻微漏水
Captain, engine room reports minor flooding from shaft seals and brine pump.
- 舱底水位18英寸 上升中 - 好
- Bilge is at 18 inches and rising. - Very well.
会潜多深?
How deep does this thing go?
不停止 一直潜到水底
She'll go all the way to the bottom if we don't stop her.
不过 通常不会深过150尺
Normally we try not to get below 150 feet.
再深 就不够力排水
Any deeper, the leaks overwhelm the pumps.
这种老爷艇
These S- boats are antiques,
年龄大过多数船员
older than most of the crew.
- 100英尺 - 好
- One- zero- zero feet. - Aye.
借过 埃米特长官
Excuse me, Mr. Emmett.
用双股细缆暂时扎住
Put a pipe patch on it, lash it with marline.
- 回船坞才修理 - 是 长官
- The yard can fix it when we get back to port. - Aye, sir.
放心 先生们 她虽然老 但老而弥坚
Relax, gentlemen. She's old, but she'll hold.
今日凌晨三点
Last night, at 0300 hours,
一艘英国驱逐舰报告其用深水炸弹炸沉一艘德国U艇
a British destroyer reported depth charging and sinking a German U- boat.
可是 此后一段时间
However, some time thereafter,
盟军监测站探测到敌人的无线电信号...
Allied direction finding stations triangulated a coded enemy radio signal...
这处发出来 接近战区分野线
to this position here, near the chop line.
我们相信那艘U型潜艇只是不能动 没沉没
We believe the U- boat was disabled, not sunk,
它正沿着四节的洋流向东漂流
and is drifting eastward on a four- knot current.
现在 法国抵抗组织报告一艘德国补给潜艇...
Now, French resistance reported a resupply submarine...
昨天下午从洛里昂U艇围栏出航
sailed from the Lorient U- boat pens yesterday afternoon,
带着引擎零件和维修技师
with engine parts and mechanics.
我们相信它会与不能动的U型艇会合
We believe it's gonna rendezvous with the disabled U- boat.
U型潜艇上有这个机器
On board that U- boat is this.
- 打字机? - 密码机
- A typewriter? - An Enigma code machine.
能让德国海军的潜艇之间进行加密通讯
It allows the German navy to communicate with its submarines in secret,
我们破解不到通讯 所以吃败仗
and our inability to decipher their messages is costing us this war.
库南长官
Mr. Coonan.
计划基本上就是特洛伊木马
All right, this is basically a Trojan Horse operation.
我们S33号假扮成德国补给潜艇
The S-33 will rendezvous with the U- boat,
跟那艘U型潜艇会合
posing as the German resupply sub.
我带领一支穿着德国海军制服
I will lead a boarding party dressed in
的登船队前往敌方潜艇
Kriegsmarine uniforms to the enemy submarine.
我们夺取那艘U艇并确保密码机的安全
We will take it by force and secure the Enigma.
把战俘押回S33
Any German survivors will be transferred to the S-33,
然后注水沉没U艇
and the U- boat will be scuttled.
德国补给潜艇赶到现场...
The German resupply submarine will arrive at the rendezvous...
会以为U艇伤重沉没
and will assume that the U- boat succumbed to its wounds and sank.
德国人决不能怀疑我们得到了密码机
The Germans must never suspect we have the Enigma.
这点至关重要
That is vital.
所以 这是竞速?
So it's a race?
对 很准确
Yes, effectively.
谁登上U艇?
Who's the boarding party?
既然你是执行官 就是你了 长官
Well, since you're the X.O., you, sir.
埃米特 拉森 赫希 以及九名船员
Mr. Emmett, Mr. Larson, Mr. Hirsch and nine of your ship's company.
舰长 当然会留在S33号上
The captain, of course, will remain onboard the S-33.
库南先生 我们的船员只是潜艇水手
Mr. Coonan, our boys are submarine sailors,
不是陆战队战斗人员
not combat Marines.
U艇的船员也是
The boys onboard that U- boat are sailors too.
你的人会准备好的 上尉 我会亲自训练他们
Your men'll be ready, Lieutenant. I'll train them myself.
你来对船了
You've come to the right boat.
好 士官长 试试开动
Okay,Chief. Let's give it a test.
你说过懂得修理?
You said you could repair engines?
舰长 我只跟我叔叔学过修摩托车
Captain,I apprenticed in my Uncle's garage, fixing scooters.
我需要的是机械师
I need a mechanic!
喂 朋友
Ahoy! Friends!
我们有很多伤员
Stop! We have many wounded!
请俘虏我们吧
Take us prisoner, please!
舰长 他们说什么?
What are they saying, Captain?
我们不会添麻烦
We'll be no trouble.
帮帮我们
Give us a hand!
他们想做俘虏
They desire to be our guests.
不可能 射死他们
Impossible. Shoot them.
元首命令过 不准救援任何人
Standing orders of the Fuhrer. We will not pick up any survivors.
我们需要水...
We need water...
- 如果他们被发现 会报告我们的位置 - 还有食物
- If they are found, they will report our position with much eagerness. - and food.
我们只想回家
We just want to get home!
开枪
Get on with it.
我们没...
We have no...
我这个女友简直风骚得要命
I'm telling you, she was hotter than Dorothy Lamour.
- 真的? - 分明对我有兴趣
- Really? - Yeah, I could tell she was interested,
她好有品味
but she was classy, you know?
属于出入乡村俱乐部那类
The type of girl that wants you to take her to a country club dance.
难道你进过乡村俱乐部
Yeah? Like you've ever seen the inside of a country club?
请我我也未必进去
Hey! Like I'd even want to, all right?
我发动追求 但没有什么进展
Anyway, I can see I'm not getting anywhere with her,
所以我所做的就是 使用我的秘密武器
so what I do is, I use my secret weapon.
告诉她S26潜艇的事 立即见功
I tell her about the S-26. Does the trick right away.
在我们出航的时候不要谈论这个
Don't be talking about that while we're underway.
为什么? S26发生了什么事? 什么回事?
Why? What happened with the S-26? Yeah, what happened?
- 你们不知道? - 不知道
- You guys don't know? - No. No.
S26在诺福克进行测试下潜
She was running a test dive down off Norfolk.
轴密封失灵
Shaft seal failed.
她沉到了400英尺
She sunk to 400 feet.
400尺深 水压有多厉害吗?
Know how much water pressure there is that deep?
马佐拉 这次出海不准你吃鸡蛋
Mazzola, you will be the first one eating powdered eggs on this cruise.
听到没有?
Keep it up, you hear?
进来
Come in.
舰长 这是我们目前的位置
This is our position, Captain.
我们还在逆浪而行
We're still bucking some pretty heavy seas.
风浪大 我们迟了三小时
I estimate us to be about three hours behind schedule.
我吩咐埃米特长官全速前航 稳定深度...
I told Mr. Emmett to run at flank speed and hold off a trim dive...
- 直到我们赶上时间 - 好 上尉
- until we make up the lost time. - That's fine, Lieutenant.
你是一流的执行官 安迪
You're a first-rate X.O., Andy.
一个该死的优秀潜艇艇员
A damn good submariner.
我知道船员喜欢你
I know the men like you.
我愿意为他们任何一个付出生命 长官
I'd give my life for any one of them, sir.
我知道你会 我没有质疑你的勇气
I know you would. I'm not questioning your bravery.
问题是 关于他们的生命呢?
The question is: What about their lives?
你和埃米特是好朋友
You and Mr. Emmett are good friends.
一起上军校
Went to the Academy together.
你愿意牺牲他的生命吗?
Would you be willing to sacrifice his life?
或者那些年轻的士兵呢?
Or what about some of the younger enlisted men?
你知道 很多那些小伙子把你当作兄长
You know, a lot of those guys look up to you like a big brother.
你愿意让他们冒极大的生命危险吗?
You willing to lay their lives on the line?
你看你犹豫了
You see you hesitate.
但作为舰长 你不能犹豫
But as a captain, you can't.
你不得不行动
You have to act.
如果你不果断 你就会危及全体船员
If you don't, you put the entire crew at risk.
这就是工作 这不是一门学科
Now that's the job. It's not a science.
你必须能够根据不完善的信息
You have to be able to make hard decisions,
做出艰难的决定
based on imperfect information.
要求手下执行可能结果导致死亡的命令
Asking men to carry out orders that may result in their deaths.
而如果你错了 你就要承担后果
And if you're wrong, you suffer the consequences.
如果你不准备做出这些决定...
If you're not prepared to make those decisions...
没有停顿 没有思考
without pause, without reflection,
那你就没有资格成为潜艇舰长
then you've got no business being a submarine captain.
告诉赫希 我想见他 好吗?
Tell Mr. Hirsch I'd like a word with him, would you?
是 长官
Aye, sir.
- 还要汤吗 舰长? - 谢谢
- More soup, Captain? - Thank you.
可以跟你们去就好
I wish I was going with you, gentlemen.
我也希望去 卡尔森
I feel the same way you do, Carson.
各位 我想祝酒
Gentlemen, I'd like to propose a toast.
谨祝S33全体官兵...
To the officers and crew of the S-33...
我们的两位客人 赫希和库南
distinguished guests, Mr. Hirsch and Mr. Coonan.
- 马到成功 - 马到成功
- Success, gentlemen! - Success. Success.
- 达尔格伦舰长 长官? - 什么事 温兹?
- Captain Dahlgren, sir? - What is it, Wentz?
士官长说 70度发现无线电通讯
Chief says we've picked up a radar contact at 0- 7- 0.
非常好 拉森
Very well. Mr. Larson
右船首在打信号灯
Signal lamp off the starboard bow!
我看见了
I see it.
传令下去 在右舷船头发现潜艇
Pass the word along: Submarine sighted off the starboard bow.
- 战斗岗位待命 - 是 舰长
- Stand by to man battle stations. - Aye, sir.
好 开始吧 最后一次
All right, here we go. One last time.
泰勒上尉那组占领指挥塔后方
Lieutenant Tyler's raft gets from the conning tower aft.
我的组拿下艇炮手
My raft gets the gun crew.
除非我先开枪 谁也不准开枪
And no one... no one... shoots till I shoot first.
- 你们明白了吗? - 明白 长官
- You read me? - Yes, sir.
好极了 上弹
Outstanding. Lock and load.
没事的 孩子
It'll be all right, son.
舰长 德国补给潜艇时速14节
Captain, I estimate the German resupply sub has a 14- knot speed of advance.
- 就是说12小时后驶到 长官 - 很好 拉森
- My latest plot puts them at 12 hours away, sir. - Very well, Mr. Larson.
舰长 登艇队准备就绪 长官 等待你的命令
Captain, the boarding party's ready, sir. Await your go-ahead.
我会潜在水里 我想让那艘潜艇的轮廓尽可能小
Put her low in the water. I wanna give that U- boat as little silhouette as we can.
长官? 准备让登船人员下船
Sir? Prepare to disembark the boarding party.
好的 舰长
Aye, Captain.
如果失败的话
If this thing goes south,
我会轰掉那艘纳粹潜艇
I will blow that Nazi boat right out of the water.
- 明白 舰长 - 好
- Understood, sir. - Very well.
准备就绪 舰长
All set, Captain.
听著
Now you listen to me.
拿到密码机 立即回来
You get them their damn trophy and get the hell outta there.
是 舰长
Aye, sir.
这班小伙子靠得住
The boys are gonna be fine.
我知道 舰长
I know they will, sir.
祝你好运 安迪
Good luck, Andy.
主佑你 舰长
Godspeed, Skipper.
我们的带来鲜蛋
Our comrades have brought us fresh eggs,
香蕉 甚至还有家书
bananas and even our mail.
镇定点 赫希长官
Easy, Mr. Hirsch.
快到了
We're almost there.
杀他们一个措手不及
We'll bushwhack 'em real good.
甲板上共12个人 瞭望台3个
All right, we got 12 men topside, three on the bridge,
艇首4个 艇尾5个
four on the foredeck, five aft.
记着 绑好两艘橡皮艇才行动
Now remember: Both rafts need to be tied up before we move.
上帝 他们有机枪
Jesus H. Christ. They got machine guns.
大家镇定
Steady, gentlemen.
等待号令
Wait for the signal.
喂
Ahoy!
赫希长官
Mr. Hirsch.
喂 欢迎啊
Ahoy! Welcome.
这次靠你们的修理功夫了
Have we got a job for you.
赫希长官
Mr. Hirsch.
- 笨蛋 打招呼吧 - 住嘴
- Hello the boat, you asshole. - Shut up.
你真该死 赫希 说话啊
Goddamn you, Hirsch, say something.
你们谁是机械技师?
Which of you are the mechanics?
我们都是 技术一流
We're all mechanics. And we're all very skilled.
日出前 你们一定可以起航
We'll have you underway before dawn.
喂
Ahoy!
谁想来点刺激的?
Who wants this junk?
黄色书信 上面撒满法国香水
Pornography and dirty letters stinking of French perfume.
满满一袋
A sack of pure shit.
我先给你们扔上去
I should throw it overboard.
欢迎登船
Welcome aboard.
快上 登上这船 离开橡皮艇
Let's go! Board this thing! Get out of the rafts!
击退敌人 紧急下潜
Repel Boarders! Alarm dive!
指挥塔 上 上
Conning tower! Move, move!
歼灭塔上敌军
Clear the conning tower now!
还有一个
Another one there!
- 格力斯中枪 - 让他去
- Griggs is hit! - Get him off!
快 扳机 后面去
Move, move! Trigger, on the back!
格力斯 格力斯
Griggs! Griggs!
- 我们要进去 - 格力斯
- We gotta get inside! - Griggs!
士官长 坦克 下去
Chief, Tank, come down now!
准备?
Ready?
快打开 开枪
Quick, open it! Fire!
泰勒 我们下去 下去
Tyler, let's go! Inside!
掩护你的手下 下去
Cover your men! Go, go!
别让他们关上 别让他们关上
Don't let 'em close it. Don't let 'em close it!
尽快潜下去
Flood all the tanks!
把他们淹死 快让开
Let's drown these vermin! Move your asses!
快 下潜 下潜
Faster! Take her down, down!
2 3 4 5 仍
Two, three, four, five. Shut it.
快冲 快下去
Let's go. Go! Get down! Go!
快 下去 下去 快
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
退后 退后 别动 别动
Get off him, get off him! Don't move, don't move! Get back, get back!
放下武器
Just drop it! Drop it!
押他们出去
Get 'em outta here! Get 'em outta here!
- 打中你了? - 我没事 长官
- Did they hit you? - I'm okay, sir.
船尾组 搜 船首组 搜
Stern team, go! Bow team, go!
我没子弹了 长官 你先上
I'm outta clips, sir. You go ahead.
- 兔子 - 好了 押他们出去
- Rabbit! - All right, get 'em outta here.
跟我来 把他们带出去 蹲下 蹲下
Get 'em outta here! Let's go! Get down! Down, down, down, down! Get down!
好了 谁是舰长? 谁是舰长?
All right, who's the captain? Huh? Who's the captain?
舰长? 混蛋 你是不是舰长?
Capitan? How about you, ugly? You the captain, huh?
扳机 如果有人动 你就对前面的开枪 明白了吗?
Trigger, if anybody moves, you shoot 'em right here in the forehead, understand?
- 是 长官 - 好
- Yes, sir! - All right.
赫希 找到了
Hirsch, we got it.
出来 蹲下
Get down, down!
- 蹲在这 - 蹲下
- Down there! - Down, down!
兔子 检查舱底有没有埋炸药 把你的枪给我
Rabbit, check the bilge for a scuttling charge. Give me your weapon!
- 快点 快点 - 是的
- Move, sailor, move! - Aye, sir!
不准动
Goddamn it, stay there.
赫希 我觉得这是密码本
Hirsch, I think we got the code books!
墨水正在溶化 快点抹干
That ink's running. Dry it.
是水溶性墨水
It's water soluble.
就用毯子
Yeah, use the blankets, use the blankets.
没有炸药 埃米特长官
Nothing but pipes and valves, Mr. Emmett.
船首受控
Bow compartment secure.
这群胆死鬼
Bunch of Marys.
你好 你现在是10号了
How you doing? You're number ten. There you go.
今晚好
You having a good night? Uh- huh.
你们丢掉潜艇 元首可不高兴
Ain't gonna be none too happy you lost his boat.
幸运号码11号
Lucky number eleven, let's go!
初次见到黑人 是吧?
It's your first time looking at a black man, ain't it?
见得多就惯了
Get used to it.
走 过来
Let's go! Get over here!
快 还有一个钟头就日出
All right, hurry it up. It's gonna be sunup in an hour.
导火索在烧 长官
Fuse is burning, sir.
好 她在烧 把货搬上橡皮艇
All right, she's burning! Let's get this raft loaded!
快
Let's move!
长官 所有战俘已经押上S33
Sir, we got all the prisoners transferred to the S-33.
好
Very well.
嘿 安迪
Hey, Andy.
注意别落下东西 一定要保护好
Make sure you got everything! Get it in the raft!
东西都放到甲板下 开始吧
Get everything belowdecks. Let's go!
快回舱去 有敌袭击
Everybody, belowdecks! Get down!
士官长 潜下去
Chief, take her down! Aye, sir!
- 赫希 走 - 密码机
- Let's go, Hirsch! - The Enigma!
大家下甲板
Everybody belowdecks.
扳机 抓住
Trigger! Grab hold!
好了 扳机
Trigger! Attaboy!
- 拿到了 - 救命
- Got it! - Help me! Help me! Oh, no! No!
- 我们要走了 - 快点 快走
- We gotta get outta here! - Come on, let's go.
- 水上还有人 - 我们走
- There's still men in the water. - Let's go.
长官 还有人在水里呢
Chief, there's still men in the water.
快走
Go!
安迪 安迪
Andy! Andy!
快
Go!
快下潜
Dive!
快潜下去
Take her down! Take her down!
快潜
Dive!
泰勒 我们走吧
Tyler, let's go!
- 士官长 找到水柜控制没有 - 上面全是德文
- Chief, you find those vents? - Everything's in German!
- 兔子 到鱼雷室 - 是 长官
Rabbit, get to the torpedo room. - Aye, sir.
通话机在哪
Where's the goddamn 1 MC?
- 扳机 你掌舵 - 长官
- Trigger, get on the helm! - Sir.
- 马佐拉 你操作平衡翼 - 收到
- Mazzola, take the planes! - Aye, sir.
- 温兹 这是什么 - 不知道 没有标识
- Wentz, what about these? - I don't know, there's no label!
这两个是后水柜控制阀
Okay, those are the aft ballast tanks vents!
中舱阀 主通气阀
These are the midship vents, and these are the main induction valves.
- 全都关上 - 坦克 我需要船动起来
- Make sure they're shut. - Tank, I need speed!
设法用电力开动螺旋桨
Get the screws turning.
- 指示灯亮了 电池还有电 - 我看不懂
- The lights are on, so there's got to be some power left. - I can't read this!
兔子 看看还有多少鱼雷
Rabbit, find out how many fish we've got in the tubes!
搞懂怎么发射 快
Figure out how to launch 'em! Go!
我看不懂
I can't read this!
赫希 去帮帮坦克
Go help Tank, Hirsch. Go, Hirsch!
找控制板
Find the Christmas tree.
确定所有舱盖关好
We've gotta make sure we don't have any holes in the boat!
“卡拉 卡拉 卡拉” 温兹 “卡拉”是什么意思?
"Klar, klar, klar." Wentz, what the hell is "klar"?
"卡拉"指"安全" 所有舱盖关好
"Klar" means "clear." All compartments secure.
- 白灯就是绿灯吗? - 白灯就是绿灯
- White for green? - White for green.
舱盖关好 潜下去 士官长
No holes in the ship! Dive the boat, Chief!
开启注水阀 开启中舱阀
Opening ballast vents! Opening midship valves!
开启中舱阀
Opening midship vents!
这是前均衡控制 后均衡控制
This is forward trim, aft trim. These are auxiliaries.
主发动机 辅助发动机
Main motor. Auxiliary, auxiliary.
这是公制 全部都是
This is in meters. Everything's in meters.
潜经15米
Passing 15 meters.
- 建议关闭主气阀 - 可以
Recommend shutting main vents! - Make it so!
- 温兹 去声纳室 - 好的
- Wentz, get in the sound room! - Yes, sir!
- 潜至20米 - 是
- Make depth 20 meters. - Depth 20 meters, aye.
- 士官长 监督下潜 - 正在监督下潜
- Chief, take the dive! - I have the dive.
20米 船首下衡翼零度 用尾翼控制深度
At 20 meters. Bow planes at zero. Control your depth with the stern planes.
首翼零度 用尾翼控制
Bow planes at zero. Controlling down with the stern planes.
见鬼 长官 全速前进
Oh, shit. All ahead full, sir!
电池快耗尽
Batteries are flat and draining fast!
泰勒长官 我听到S33爆炸 等一等
Mr. Tyler, I hear the S-33 breaking up. Wait.
10度有德国潜艇
I hold a submerged U- boat, 0- 1- 0.
好接近 在1000码内
Real close. Less than 1,000 yards.
- 该死的补给潜艇 我们方向? - 280度 长官
- Goddamn resupply sub. What's our heading? - Two- eight- zero, sir!
满舵右转 按10度前航
All right, right full rudder! Steady on 0- 1- 0!
是 满舵右转 按10度前航
Aye, sir! Right full rudder. Steady on course 0- 1- 0, sir.
坦克 右车急倒转 兔子 答话
Tank, starboard back full. Rabbit, get back to me.
右引擎急倒车 是 长官
Starboard back full. Aye, sir.
- 注意深度 防止艇尾下垂 - 兔子
- Watch your depth. She'll squat. - Rabbit!
有四枚鱼雷 发射管灌水了
We got four fish. Tubes are flooded,
但我打不开门 等我平衡水压
but I can't open the doors until I'm equalized.
- 我找不到阀门 - 温兹 帮兔子
- I can't find the valve! - Wentz, help Rabbit!
敌潜艇靠近
Enemy submarine close aboard.
鱼雷入水 鱼雷已入水
Torpedo in the water. Torpedo in the water!
好 你不用帮兔子 温兹 留下
All right, belay that. Wentz, stay where you are!
赫希 快去鱼雷室
Hirsch, hotfoot it to the torpedo room!
- 方向舵 每10度报告方向 - 是 长官
- Helm, mark your head every ten degrees. - Aye, sir.
- 现在是320度 - 转弯 转弯
- Now passing 3- 2- 0. - Turn, baby, turn. Turn!
平衡阀 真见鬼 什么啊什么?
Equalizing valves. Holy shit! What's what?
这是疯了 我没法平衡发射管
This is crazy. I can't equalize the tubes!
- 你要找什么? 阀门? - 平衡阀 平衡阀
- What do you need? Valve? - Equalizing valves! Equalizing valves!
- 回转仪? - 不 排水阀? - 排水阀 不
- Gyro? - No, drainage. - Drainage. No.
现在转经0度
Now passing 0- 0- 0.
转快点 杂种 转快点
Swing, you bastard, swing.
士官长 在这等着 前衡水舱可能需要注水
Chief, stand by in case we have to flood forward trim.
- 脉冲阀? - 不是 - 差...压力差阀?
- Impulse? - No - Differential... Pressure differential?
- 转动它们 对 快转动它们 - 哪个方向?
- Turn 'em! Yes, turn 'em! - Which way?
逆时针
Counterclockwise.
鱼雷未中 经过我们的船尾
Torpedo missed. It's in our baffles.
两枚鱼雷入水
Two more torpedoes in the water!
U艇准确方位:10度
Best bearing to the U- boat: 0- 1- 0.
好 兔子 准备扇型发射鱼雷
Aye, Rabbit, get ready to fire a spread.
1和2号管 零度回转 发射
Tubes one and two. Zero gyro. Fire!
兔子 发射
Rabbit, fire!
什么事?
What's going on?
- 什么声音? - 有问题 鱼雷卡住了
- What is that? - Wrong one! The fish is stuck!
我们有时候会错过一个联动装置
We missed an interlock sometime.
兔子 趁鱼雷没爆炸赶快发射
Rabbit, get those fish out before they blow!
找"压缩气"或者"发射气"
Look for "impulse air" or "firing air."
"压缩气" 那里和那里
That was "impulse" there and there!
1 2号鱼雷射出 3 4号待命
One, two, away. Lining up tubes three and four.
3 4号 发射
Three and four, fire!
鱼雷统统正确射出
All fish running hot, straight and normal.
我觉得都没射中 长官
I think they all missed, sir.
棒极了
Shit.
敌艇爆炸
U- boat's breaking up!
我听到舱壁崩溃
I hear bulkheads collapsing.
救援S33号潜艇 泰勒长官
The 33 boat, Mr. Tyler.
上升搜寻生还者 士官长
Let's take her up and look for survivors, Chief.
- 平衡翼向上 - 收到
- Give me some rise on the planes! - Rise on the planes, aye.
主水柜排水
Deploy main ballast!
拉到你了
Gotcha.
见鬼
Oh, crap.
救命
Help!
救命呀
救命...
Please! Help!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
会讲英语吗?
Do you speak English?
你会讲英语吗?
English. Do you speak English?
什么军衔
What's your rank?
你是做什么的?
What do you do?
负责什么?
What's your job? Your job.
职位
"Job."
电工
Electrician
你是电工 很好
You're an electrician. Good.
你可以帮我们多弄点电力出来
You can help us squeeze more juice out of them batteries.
打扰一下 长官 我看到舰长了
I'm sorry, sir, I see the skipper.
电池没电了
Battery's dead.
刚才已经把剩余电力全部用完了
Whatever juice was left we used up when we maneuvered.
柴油机呢?
What about the diesels?
右引擎毁坏了 需要进船坞修理
Starboard's a wreck. We need the dry dock to fix it.
左引擎有得救
Port side diesel's the good news.
那些德国捞完全是外行
Whoever the Krauts had on it didn't know a piston head from his sister's titty.
我有把握修好
I think I can fix it.
好吧 坦克
Okay, Tank.
尽力而为
Do what you can.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
大家听著
All right. Listen up.
航线是这样
We've decided on a course.
我们往英国南端驶去
We're headin' for England, Land's End.
除了法国沦陷区外 那处最近
It's the closest, besides occupied France.
兔子 还剩几枚鱼雷
Rabbit, how many torpedoes do we have?
仅仅船尾一枚 而且有故障
Just one. It's in the stern tube, which is busted.
压缩气管在漏气
Bleedin' air from somewhere.
- 长官? - 什么事 扳机?
- Sir? - Yeah, what is it, Trigger?
为什么不用无线电
Can't we just use the radio,
发求救讯号 等候救援?
fire off a Mayday and wait for a rescue?
不可能的
That's impossible.
如果我们发送信号 德军会找到我们的位置...
If we transmit, the Germans will direction- find our position to a grid...
还有他们的两艘沉艇
with their missing two U- boats.
如果他们怀疑我们得到密码机
If they even suspect we have the Enigma,
他们就会更改整个编码系统
they will change their entire coding system.
这样一来 我们就前功尽弃
And that would completely negate the purpose of our mission.
泰勒长官
Mr. Tyler,
如果我们驶向英格兰
if we head for England,
我们将直接穿过西部海域
we're gonna go straight through the western approaches.
他说得对 那是德国佬的地盘
He's right. I mean, that's Jerry's backyard.
现在 听着 伙计们
Now, listen, guys.
全是U型潜艇
It's full of U- boats.
我们没有招架之力
And we've got nothing to defend ourselves with.
你们以为我知道脱险的办法吗?
Do you think I got all the answers here?
以为我有逃离这里的办法吗?
Think I know how we're gonna get out of this?
没有 我也不知道
I don't. I don't know how.
- 我建议用无线电 - 没人问你
- I say we use the radio. - Nobody asked you.
- 用无线电搏一搏 - 说了不行
- We use the radio and take our chances. - I said can it.
- 舰长会用... - 舰长已经殉职
- It's what the captain would have done it... - Captain's dead.
你发疯了
This is crazy.
这想法简直疯了
This whole thing is crazy.
宁要打字机 不要命
Riskin' our lives over a typewriter.
这不是打字机
It's not a typewriter.
是打字机 有键盘
The hell it ain't. It's got buttons like a typewriter.
对 好吧 不是打字机
Yeah, well, it's not.
无论是什么 让我们被杀这太疯狂了
Whatever it is, it's crazy we get killed over it.
司令部说它重要 就是重要
The navy says it's important, it's important.
司令部说比你 我 他都重要
The navy says it's more important than you, him, me, fine.
我们就得拼命去夺取
We're gonna die trying.
那样不是发疯 是职责
And that ain't crazy. That's our job.
我不明白 士官长 你为什么不担任指挥?
What I don't understand, Chief, is how come you're not in charge?
传言说戴格伦打算把泰勒踢出海军
Scuttlebutt is Dahlgren was kicking Tyler out of the navy anyway,
大家对这他也…
and everybody get this one...
你太放肆了 水手
You stow that shit right now, sailor.
泰勒上尉是你的指挥官
Lieutenant Tyler is your commanding officer,
而你要尊重那个人
and you will respect that man as such.
- 你知道吗? - 知道 士官长
- Do you understand? - Yes, Chief.
瞧他们这帮狗娘养的
Look at them sons of bitches.
知道我父亲是渔民吗?
You know my pop was a fisherman?
他那艘渔船60英尺长
He had this old 60- footer he'd run all over the gulf.
用嘈杂的两冲程柴油机推动
Noisy two stroke diesel.
船身破得不成样子
Rotten to the gunnels, that thing.
我每日洗擦甲板三次依然腥臭熏天
I could scrub that deck three times a day, and it still stunk like fish.
我发誓不做那样的舰长
But I swore I'd never skipper a boat like that, Chief.
哼
Hmm,
我立志要做战船的指挥
I saw myself standin' on the bridge of a battleship.
做个真正的舰长
A real sea captain.
泰勒长官 我想率直说句话
Mr. Tyler, permission to speak freely?
当然可以
Of course, Chief.
这是在海军
This is the navy,
指挥官有无限威严
where a commanding officer is a mighty and terrible thing,
是个可敬可畏的人
a man to be feared and respected.
他无所不知 无所不能
All knowing, all powerful.
你决不可再说"不知道"
Don't you dare say what you said to the boys back there again."I don't know."
那三个字像深水炸弹 能要大家命
Those three words will kill a crew, dead as a depth charge.
你现在是舰长了
You're the skipper now,
无论如何 舰长总有办法
and the skipper always knows what to do, whether he does or not.
- 左船头有飞机 - 见鬼
- Aircraft off the port bow! - Shit!
对不起 飞机突然从云中出现
Real sorry, sir. It dropped right out of the clouds.
兔子 扳机 高射炮旁戒备
Rabbit, Trigger, stand by the flak gun.
舰长 舰长
Sir. Sir.
是德国飞机 似乎是远程侦察机
It's German. Looks like long- range reconnaissance.
为什么飞到这里来
What the hell's it doing way out here?
它过来了 大家要镇定
Jesus, here it comes. All right. Sit tight.
他只知道我们是友军 大家挥手
As far as he knows, we're all playing on the same team. Everybody wave.
挥手
Wave?
不如先发制人 发炮射下来
Sir, we're sittin' ducks. If we shoot first, we can blow 'em out of the sky.
万一没打中 他会召来敌舰
We shoot, we miss, he's gonna radio us in.
到时更麻烦
That plane's gonna be the least of our problems.
真疯了 迟早连累我们死掉
This is crazy. You're gonna get us killed.
他掉头了 他掉头了
He's comin' around. He's comin' around!
会攻击 兔子 开枪
He's attacking! Rabbit, do something!
- 马佐拉 闭嘴 兔子 别理他 - 开枪
- Mazzola, shut up. Rabbit, ignore him. - Do something!
它朝我们直冲过来 兔子
It's coming straight for us, Rabbit!
它朝我们直冲过来 分开它们 做点什么
It's coming right at us! Split them up, do something!
- 听我说 水手帕克 - 你还等什么?
- Acknowledge me, Seaman Parker. - What are you waiting for?
- 对 兔子 开枪 - 水手帕克 我命令你
- Yeah, Rabbit! Shoot him! - Seamen Parker, I'm ordering you!
不准开枪 松开扳机
Do not fire that weapon! Get your finger off that trigger!
别听他的 兔子 开枪
Don't listen to him, Rabbit, shoot him!
- 开枪 开枪 - 我们要死了
- Pull the trigger! Pull the trigger! - We're gonna die!
- 开枪啊 - 听指挥 兔子
- Do it! Do it! - Come on! Goddamn it, can't you see him?
你他娘的在干嘛?
What the hell are you doin', huh?
这不是在搞民主投票
This is not a goddamn democracy!
泰勒长官 水平线上有船来
Mr. Tyler, I see a mast on the horizon!
见鬼 纳粹驱逐舰
Shit! That's a Nazi destroyer.
那飞机必定为驱逐舰侦察
That plane must have been runnin' a recon screen for it.
下甲板去 士官长 关闭舱盖 下潜
Clear the bridge! Chief, secure the diesel and dive the ship!
马上下潜 收到 长官
Dive the ship! Aye, sir!
控制灯没有变绿 机房未锁好
We don't have a green board. The engine room's not ready.
水柜不能打开 液压下降
Vents won't open We lost hydraulics.
坦克 锁紧机房开动引擎潜水
Tank, secure the diesel and rig the engine room for dive!
坦克 答话
Tank, acknowledge!
马佐拉 去看看什么事
Goddamn it! Mazzola, go see what the hell's going on back there.
枪放下 纳粹杂种
Drop it, you Nazi son of a bitch! Drop it!
天 混蛋
Goddamn it.
很对不起 泰勒长官
I'm real sorry, Mr. Tyler.
没想到他会偷袭
Took me right off my feet.
听着 你一定要锁好机房
Listen to me. You've got to secure the diesel.
尽快打开水柜注水阀
And find out why the vent valves won't open now!
- 好的 - 见鬼
- Yes, sir. - Goddamn it!
- 爱迪 把杂种的手脚锁在床上 - 是
Eddie, get this son of a bitch out of here. Chain him to the bunks. - Yes, sir.
确保他动弹不得 让他屈服
Make sure his hands and feet are secure. Put him into submission!
- 长官 有大麻烦了 - 照看他 爱迪
Sir, we have a big problem! - Take care of it, Eddie.
惨了
Oh, shit.
叫坦克赶紧修理 敌舰派了人来
Tell Tank to finish those repairs. The destroyer is sending a launch.
他要五分钟
He needs five minutes, Mr. Tyler!
五分钟来不及
We don't have five minutes, Chief.
上尉 用机关炮 如果从水下射击
Lieutenant, the deck cannon. If we fire a shell below the water line.
一点用没有
It wouldn't do a goddamn thing.
驱逐舰承受得住上百发子弹
No, that tub could take a hundred shells.
我们需要的是可以用的鱼雷 但我们没有
What we need is a working torpedo, which we do not have.
扳机 在高射炮上待命
Trigger, stand by on the flak gun.
等我命令 扫射橡皮艇
When I give the word, turn that launch into driftwood.
收到
Yes, sir.
60秒内他们就会识穿我们
Gonna find out who we are in about 60 seconds.
扳机 准备扫射?
Trigger, ready on that weapon?
士官长 告诉坦克还有一分钟
Chief, tell Tank he has one minute,
叫温兹 兔子提冲锋枪上来
and get Wentz and Rabbit up here with the machine gun.
赫希 他们识穿我们身份 会怎样?
Hirsch, what happens when they find out we're not German?
把我们当间谍射杀 并且通知德军总部
Well, after they shoot us as spies so, they'll radio into headquarters.
报告密码被夺
They'll tell them the Enigma's been compromised.
不如在他们通知前毁掉他们的无线电?
What if we take out their radio, before they can notify anyone about us?
怎样摧毁?
How?
用甲板机关炮射击
With that deck gun.
尽管难度很大 但可以做到
It's gonna be one hell of a shot, but we can do it.
随后我们下潜 躲在驱逐舰舰底
Then we dive like hell, and we get under them quick.
我们引诱他们离大陆更近一点
We lure 'em a little bit closer to the continent,
进入盟军的空中掩护范围
in range of Allied air cover.
- 然后叫空军来轰炸 - 对 叫空军来轰炸
- Then we call in an air strike. - Yeah, we call in an air strike.
德国佬割穿了液压管
Son of a bitch cut off pressure to the hydraulics.
我们要找止漏阀
We need to find the stop valve.
倒霉
Damn!
看到指挥塔那座天线了吗?
See that structure topside with the big antenna sticking out of it?
- 是的 长官 - 那是无线电发射台
- Yes, sir. - That's the radio shack.
你和温兹操作甲板机关炮 我一发令
You and Wentz get on the deck. On my command,
你向发射台发炮
I want you put a shell right through the porthole.
- 去吧 两位 - 收到 长官
- Get to it, gentlemen. Get to it. - Yes, sir!
嗨 朋友
Hello, Gentlemen.
帮我们绑缆
Give us a hand with the lines.
好 等一下
Okay, wait minute.
他们干什么?
What are they doing?
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
叫他们走 赫希
Tell them to go away, Mr. Hirsch.
回去
Go back.
回舰上去
Back to the ship!
报告情况 兔子
Talk to me, Rabbit!
甲板炮配备齐全 准备就绪 长官
Deck gun manned and ready in all respects, sir!
开炮
Fire!
下甲板去
Clear the deck!
操作船首炮 他们在射击
Get to the forward gun! They're firing on us!
谁在射击 长官
Who, sir?
潜艇 他们毁了无线电塔
The submarine. They're blown up our radio tower!
快点
Come on! Come on!
快点下潜
Dive! Dive! Dive! Dive!
- 为什么还不潜 - 未修理妥 长官
- Why aren't we diving? - Repairs aren't complete, sir.
- 爱迪 你掌舵 坦克 全速前航 - 收到 长官
- Eddie, man the planes. Tank, all ahead full. - Aye, sir!
- 平衡翼操作中 - 全速前航
- Aye, sir! Manning planes! - All ahead full, aye!
射得好 兔子 无线电已经报废
Nice shot, Rabbit. That radio's history.
快点
Come on.
- 我们向他们驶去 - 对
- We're heading right towards them. - That's right.
只要够近 就可以避开炮火
Their deck guns can't get to us if we're in close enough.
希望能潜到他们的龙骨以下
Let's hope we can dive and clear her keel.
找到了
That's it.
液压恢复
Hydraulics restored!
谢谢 坦克 可以了 我们在下潜
Thank you, Tank. That did it. We're going under.
潜经5米深
Passing five meters.
潜经10米深
Passing ten meters.
潜经15米深
Fifteen meters.
20米深
Twenty meters.
扳机 左满舵
Trigger, left full rudder.
坦克 三分二全速前进
Tank, all ahead two- thirds.
敌舰移动
Contact maneuvering.
高速移动
Heavy cavitation.
- 敌舰投弹 - 妈的
- Splashes. - Shit.
密集投弹
Short intervals.
爆炸深度调校到25米
Prepare charges. Set depth twenty- five.
不要靠近舱壁 赫希长官
Step away from that bulkhead, Mr. Hirsch.
爆炸的震波可以震断脊骨
The shock wave from one of these explosions can snap your spine.
士官长 你碰上过深水炸弹吗?
Chief, you ever been depth charged?
一次 临科拉湾
Once, off Murmansk,
第一次世界大战
back in World War I.
有一枚在近距离爆炸
One charge came so close,
震脱了舰长四颗牙
it rattled four teeth out of the skipper's head.
没这次接近
Wasn't even close.
控制室 右电力发动机卡死
Control, starboard E- motor's seized up.
必定被那德国佬破坏了
The German must have sabotaged it.
岂有此理
Goddamn it.
只靠一条螺旋桨我们逃脱不掉
There's no way we make it to Allied air cover creepin' along on one shaft.
趴下
Get down!
爱迪 帮助士官长
Eddie, help Chief.
是的 长官
Ye- Yes, sir.
士官长 我帮你
Mr. Chief, I got that.
坦克... 你还活着?
Tank... you alive back there?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
很好 左引擎三分二速度
Good. Port ahead two- thirds.
左引擎三分二 是 长官
Port ahead two- thirds. Aye, sir.
坦克... 能修好鱼雷管吗?
Tank... can you fix the stern tube?
不知道 泰勒长官
I don't know, Mr. Tyler.
我不想要 "不知道"
I don't want an "I don't know."
你能修好鱼雷发射管吗? 能或不能?
Can you fix the torpedo tube? Yes... or no?
能 长官 我觉得我能
Yes, sir. I think I can.
谢谢 坦克
Thank you, Tank.
士官长 潜到160米深去
Chief, make depth 1- 6- 0 meters.
那是500多英尺
That's more than 500 feet.
潜吧 士官长
Take us down, Chief.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
160米
One- six- zero meters.
- 前后平衡翼20度下潜 - 20度下潜 是 长官
- Twenty degrees dive, both planes. - Twenty degrees dive, aye, sir.
泰勒长官
Mr. Tyler, sir,
你打算对抗驱逐舰...
Do you plan on going up against a destroyer with...
仅仅用一枚鱼雷和半台发动机?
only one fish in the tube and a busted motor?
对 爱迪
Yes, I am, Eddie.
- 明智吗? 上尉 - 不是很明智
- How wise is that, Lieutenant? - Not very.
但是 你看一下 士官长
But have a look. Chief.
时速2节的潜艇
There is no way a two- knot submarine
肯定打不过时速30节的驱逐舰
can get in firing position against a 30- knot destroyer.
除非我们潜下去
Unless we go deep.
潜到160米 用前鱼雷管发射一大堆杂物
At 160 meters, we can shoot out a bunch of junk from the forward tubes.
这些杂物会重新浮出水面
It will resurface and create a debris field.
敌舰会过来检查这些杂物
Now the destroyer's gonna go to the center of that debris field,
关闭引擎 用声纳探测...
shut off its engines to make it real nice and quiet...
确定我们是不是已经被击毁
and do an acoustic search to make sure we're dead.
但我们没死
But we're not.
我们在这里 上升到潜望镜深度
See, we're here, on our way up to periscope depth.
根据升速原理
All right, principle of ascent velocity.
我们靠浮力浮上水面 浮离敌舰
Our positive buoyancy pulls us up and away from the destroyer.
等我们浮上去 用屁股向着敌舰
And when we surface, we'll be showing it our ass at 700 yards.
这个是个完美的发射位置 嘣
That is a perfect setup for a stern shot on a stationary target. Boom.
没有比这更好的办法了
It don't get much prettier than that.
我赞成 泰勒长官
All right, Mr. Tyler.
潜经130米
All right. Passing 1- 3- 0 meters.
很好
Very well.
兔子 你把马佐拉的遗体放进三号鱼雷管
Rabbit, I need you to load Mazzola's body into tube three,
穿上救生衣 确保能浮上去
and put an escape jacket onto him to make sure he floats.
把他当垃圾射上水面?
Wanna shoot him out like garbage?
他的尸体可以救我们
His body is gonna save our lives.
我为他说几句悼词
I'll say a few words for him.
赫希 帮兔子
Hirsch, go with Rabbit.
- 爱迪 能管两边吗? - 可以
- Eddie, can you man both planes? - Yes, sir.
- 泰勒长官 - 什么
- Mr. Tyler. - Yeah.
如果你不能干掉那艘驱逐舰
If you can't take out that destroyer,
就不是我们死不死的问题了
the danger is not that some of us may die.
我们没死才是麻烦
It's that some of us may live.
潜艇上的人听到和看到的事...
These men have seen and heard things...
绝不能被敌军知道
that must not be revealed to the enemy.
我们的秘密
Our secrets,
比如我们的雷达探测力
such as our radar capabilities.
我们所掌握的德国密码
Our understanding of German encryption.
敌军如果活捉我们 会严刑逼供
If we fall into German hands alive, we will be tortured without mercy.
要么你摧毁敌舰
Either you succeed in sinking that ship.
要么我们就不能被活捉
Or you must see to it that none of us survive to be captured.
愿同胞马佐拉...
We commend his soul to God...
魂归上帝 身寄碧海
and commit his body to the deep.
泰勒长官 敌舰作迂回航行
Mr. Tyler, contact is zigging.
敌舰投弹
Splashes.
敌舰愈来愈近
Contact getting closer.
继续投弹
More splashes.
坦克 把机房咸水排出海
Tank, line up to pump engine room bilge to sea.
是
Yes, sir.
兔子
Rabbit,
发射杂物
fire the tubes.
再见 马佐拉
Bye, Mazzola.
深水炸弹在我们上面爆炸
They're setting them charges too shallow.
关闭通气阀
Secure that air valve!
士官长 报告深度
Chief, what's our depth?
160米
One- six- zero meters.
- 零度平衡翼 - 是
- Zero the planes. - Zero the planes.
敌舰投弹
Splashes!
炸弹投得太密
They're too close together!
我数不清楚
I can't count them.
士官长
Chief,
潜至200米
take us to 200 meters.
潜得深 才避得开深水炸弹
We're gonna get under these damn things.
士官长
Chief,
向200米潜下去
take us to 200 meters.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
潜至200米
Making my depth 200 meters.
双平衡翼10度下潜
Ten degrees dive, both planes.
10度下潜 遵命
Ten degrees dive. Aye.
170米
One- seven- zero meters.
坦克
Tank,
船尾鱼雷管情况怎样
what's the status on the stern torpedo tube?
还有几处未修好
There's a couple things wrong.
我能操作鱼雷管 但
I can operate the muzzle door, but
我仍然在修理压缩气
I’m still working on the impulse air.
180米
One- eight- zero meters.
泰勒长官 船尾显示深度180米
Mr. Tyler, depth gauge back here says 180 meters.
谢谢你 坦克 我知道
Thanks, Tank. I know.
继续修理
Keep working.
190米
One- nine- zero meters.
200米
Two- hundred meters.
零度平衡翼
Zero the planes.
- 零度平衡翼 收到 - 零度平衡翼
- Zero the planes, aye. - Zero the planes.
上帝
Mary, mother of God.
德国佬的潜艇倒也坚固
Those Krauts sure know how to build a boat.
士官长 上升
Chief, take us up!
衡水舱排水 平衡翼全面向上
Blowing negative! Planes full rise!
顺时钟方向 赫希
Clockwise, Hirsch!
- 兔子 帮我一下 - 快 快
- Rabbit, help me out! - Go! Go!
士官长 你见到吗?
Chief, are you seeing this?
潜过了极限深度 主水柜要排水
Needle's off the scale! We have to blow main ballast tanks!
排水吧 士官长
Do it, Chief!
还在下沉
She's still going down!
水柜的水已经排干 我试试用衡水舱排水
Ballast tanks are bone dry! I'm gonna try the trim tanks!
快升 快升上去
Come on, come on, come on!
在上升了
She's going up! She's going up!
泰勒长官 我们在上升了
Mr. Tyler, we're coming up.
但水柜已经不受控
But I've lost control of the ballast tanks.
潜艇只有不断上升
I can't stop our ascent.
船尾鱼雷管怎么样?
Where are we with the stern torpedo?
管道损坏了
Piping's damaged.
压缩气管漏气 所以没有压力发射鱼雷
There's a break in the air line, so there's no pressure to launch a torpedo.
我尝试绕过气管 但止漏阀在舱底水下
I tried to bypass the leak, but it's way back in the bilge underwater.
我进不去 空间太小
There's no way to reach it. I can't fit.
- 可以派人进去吗? - 我不知道
Can somebody else get to it? - I don't know.
或者可以派小个子进去
Maybe somebody smaller.
就是兔子或者扳机
That's Rabbit or Trigger.
上升到200米
Comin' up on 200 meters.
你要挑选一个
You gotta pick one.
扳机 扳机
Trigger. Trigger,
跟坦克到船尾去
lay aft with Tank.
去吧 你有任务要完成
Move it, son. You got a job to do.
我们没有气压发射鱼雷
See, we got no air pressure to fire the torpedo.
其中一条气管有裂口
One of these pipes is busted and leaking air.
- 怎找到裂口? - 你会见到水泡 很多水泡
- How am I gonna find it? - You'll see bubbles coming out. A lot of 'em.
把裂口后面的止漏阀关闭
Find the isolation valve aft of the leak and crank it down.
- 懂了吗? - 是
- Got it? - Yeah.
这条管给你呼吸
I rigged this hose so you can breathe through it.
- 现在听着 你一关好就走 懂吗? - 好的
- Now listen to me. As soon as you finish, you get out of there. Okay? - Yeah.
我听到敌舰
I can hear her.
敌舰在减速
Making slow turns.
现在停了下来
She just stopped her screws.
他们大概看到杂物
I think they see the debris.
他们应该中计了
I think they're buying it.
180米
One- eight- zero meters.
士官长 能升慢点吗? 还没准备好
Chief, can you slow our ascent? We are not ready.
不行
Can't, sir.
只有不断升 直至浮出水面
We got a one- way ticket topside.
浮出水面而射不出鱼雷 我们死定
If we surface without a torpedo to fire, we're dead.
有两个裂口
There's two air leaks.
我能够到一个 另一个很远
I got one, but the other one's way in the back.
我需要更长的呼吸管
I need some more slack on the hose to get to it.
没有更长的呼吸管了
That's all there is.
惨了
Shit.
150米
One- five- zero meters.
有人在发摩斯密码
I hear Morse code.
什么事? 再联络我们?
What the hell is it? Are they signaling us?
说什么 温兹?
What's it saying, Wentz?
"我是U- 571 摧毁我"
"I am U- 571. Destroy me."
上升到90米
Coming up on 9- 0 meters.
敌舰开动了引擎
Sir, she's started her engines again.
泰勒长官 扳机够不着裂口
No go, Mr. Tyler. He can't reach.
扳机 一分钟后我们就浮出水面
Trigger, in one minute we're gonna hit the surface.
你明白了吗?
Do you understand me?
你无论如何都要回去再试
Now you've got to go back in there and try.
我也不想这样 但我们的命就指望这个了
I wouldn't ask you if our lives didn't depend on it.
- 对不起 长官 我去不到裂口 - 不 扳机
- Sorry, sir. I can't reach it. - No, no, Trigger.
听着
Now listen to me.
你去得到 而且一定会
You can reach it, and you will.
一定要关闭止漏阀
Now you are gonna close that valve.
我办不到 长官 我不干
I can't, Sir, I wouldn't do it!
你是我们唯一的选择
You're the only chooses we've got.
现在立即回舱底去
Now you're gonna go back down in that bilge,
把任务完成 水手
and you're gonna do your job, sailor.
- 鱼雷可以发射 通知我 - 好的 长官
Report to me the instant that torpedo's ready to fire. - Yes, sir.
30米
Thirty meters.
- 温兹 报告情况 - 敌舰开动
- Talk to me, Wentz. - Destroyer is under way.
向我们的位置逐渐驶来
Steady bearing. They're closing our position.
糟糕
Shit!
扳机 快点
Come on, Trigger!
20米 我们快露出水面
Twenty meters. Hold on. We're gonna surface.
升潜望镜
Raising scope.
看见敌舰
Got her.
敌舰向我们驶来
She's heading right for us.
- 方向舵 右转10度 - 收到
Helm, come right ten degrees. - Helm, come right ten degrees. Aye, sir!
- 当心前平衡翼 - 收到
Watch your bow planes. Aye, sir. Watching my bow planes.
坦克 开动柴油机 全速前航
Tank, start the diesel. All ahead full!
左柴油机全速前航
Port diesel ahead full!
糟糕 被他们盯住了
Shit, they've got us bracketed.
有弹来袭
Incoming!
我们中弹
We're hit! We're hit!
- 温兹 进来 - 爱迪 锁舱盖
- Wentz, get in here! - Eddie, secure that hatch!
鱼雷管还不能发射
Tube still not ready!
- 请允许弃船 - 还不可以 士官长
- Request permission to abandon ship! - Not yet, Chief.
控制室 鱼雷管可以发射
Control, aft torpedo ready in all respects!
稳定航向 兔子 稳定航向
Hold us right there, Rabbit. Hold us steady right here.
按80度方向航行 长官
Steady on bearing 8- 0 degrees, sir!
发射
Fire!
坦克 不发射我们死定了
Tank, fire right now or we die!
加油
Come on, come on.
炸个粉碎
That blew 'em right in half.
泰勒长官 你需要士官长...
Hell, Mr. Tyler, if you ever need a chief,
我随时乐意效劳
I'd go to sea with you anytime.
谢谢你 士官长
Thank you, Chief.
坦克 什么事?
Tank, you okay?
扳机淹死了
Trigger drowned.
那小伙子没有放弃 是吧?
That kid didn't give up, did he?
你也没有 泰勒长官
Neither did you, Mr. Tyler.
潜艇快沉没了
We can't keep her afloat much longer, sir.
我们弃船吧
Let's abandon ship.
泰勒长官
Mr. Tyler. Mr. Tyler.
谨把本片献给大西洋战役中英勇的盟军海军
他们奋不顾身 夺取德国潜艇密码
1941年5月9日
英国皇家海军第三护卫队斗牛犬号和奥布雷蒂亚号航母
从U-110上截获了密码机和密码本
1942年10月30日
英国皇家'海军佩塔德号'
从U-559上截获天气暗号密码
1944年6月4日
美国海军特遣部队22.3
从U-505上截获的密码机和密码本
1942年10月30日
英国皇家'海军佩塔德号'
从U-559上截获天气暗号密码